(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T21:45:04.341705",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
I say...
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
うぶ毛の小鳥たちも
Even newborn baby birds
いつか空に羽ばたたく
will soar through the sky someday,
大きな強い翼で飛ぶ
flying with big, strong wings.
諦めちゃダメなんだ
Don't ever give up,
その日が絶対来る
that day will definitely come.
君も感じてるよね
You can feel it too, can't you?
始まりの鼓動
The beat of the beginning.
明日よ変われ！
Tomorrow, change!
希望に変われ！
Transform into hope!
眩しい光に照らされて変われ START!!
Transform, illuminated by dazzling light, start!!
悲しみに閉じ込められて
Trapped within sorrow,
泣くだけの君じゃない
you're not one to just cry.
熱い胸きっと未来を切り開くはずさ
With a blazing heart, you'll surely carve open the future.
悲しみに閉じ込められて
Trapped within sorrow,
泣くだけじゃつまらない
just crying is no fun at all.
きっと 君の チカラ
I'm sure your dream's power
いまを動かすチカラ
can set the present in motion.
信じてるよ...だから START!!
I believe in you... so start!!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
雨上がりの気分で
With the mood of after the rain,
高まる期待の中で
amidst growing expectations,
躓いたことさえも 思い出にしよう
even the stumbles we'll turn into memories.
明日が咲くよ！
Tomorrow will blossom!
希望が咲くよ！
Hope will blossom!
楽しいメロディー口ずさみ咲いた DASH!!
Humming a cheerful melody, it bloomed, dash!!
喜びを受け止めて
Embrace the joy,
君と僕つながろう
let you and me connect.
迷い道やっと外へ抜け出したはずさ
We've surely broken out of the maze at last.
喜びを受け止めて
Embrace the joy,
君と僕進もう
you and I, let's move forward.
それは 遠い カケラ
Those are distant fragments,
だけど 愛しい カケラ
yet precious fragments.
彼方へと...僕は DASH!!
Toward the other side... I will dash!!
またひとつ夢が生まれ...
And once again, a dream is born...
夢が生まれた
A dream is born...
悲しみに閉じ込められて 泣くだけの君じゃない
You aren't one to just cry, locked away in sorrow.
熱い胸 きっと未来を 切り開くはずさ
With a passionate heart, you'll carve out the future.
喜びを受け止めて
Embrace the joy,
君と僕 つながろう
and let's connect, you and I.
迷い道 やっと外へ 抜け出した筈さ
We've finally broken out of the maze.
喜びを受け止めて 君と僕進むんだろう
Embrace the joy, you and I will press forward.
それは (それは) 遠い (夢の)
Those are (those are) distant (dream's)
カケラ (だけど) 愛しいカケラ
fragments (yet) precious fragments,
彼方へと 僕はDASH!!
dashing off into the distance!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
羽ばたいたら 戻らないと言って
You said if you could fly, you'd never return.
目指したのは 蒼い 蒼い あの空
What you aimed for was that blue, blue sky.
蒼い 蒼い あの空
That blue, blue sky.
悲しみはまだ覚えられず 切なさは今掴み始めた
Sadness is still unknown, and pain is just beginning.
あなたへと抱く この感情も 今“言葉”に変わっていく
The feelings I hold for you turn into words.
未知なる世界の 迷いから目覚めて この羽翼を広げ 飛び立つ
Awakening from the maze of an unknown world, I take flight.
羽ばたいたら 戻らないと言って
You said if you could fly, you'd never return.
目指したのは 白い 白い あの雲
What you aimed for was that white, white cloud.
突き抜けたら みつかると知って
Knowing you'll find it once you break through,
振り切るほど 蒼い 蒼い あの空
shaking off the blue, blue sky.
蒼い 蒼い あの空
That blue, blue sky...
駆け出したら 手にできると言って
You said if you started running, you could grasp it.
誘うのは 遠い 遠い あの声
What invited you was that far, far voice.
眩しすぎた あなたの手も握って
Holding even your blinding hand,
求めるほど 蒼い 蒼い あの空
the more I desired that blue, blue sky.
蒼い 蒼い あの空
That blue, blue sky.
羽ばたいたら 戻らないと言って
You said if you could fly, you'd never return.
目指したのは 白い 白い あの雲
What you aimed for was that white, white cloud.
突き抜けたら みつかると知って
Knowing you'll find it once you break through,
振り切るほど 蒼い 蒼い あの空
shaking off the blue, blue sky.
蒼い 蒼い あの空
That blue, blue sky...
みんなこんにちはー！
Everyone, hello!
こんばんはー！えへへへっ
Good evening! Ehehehe
え、今日は雪花ラミィのバースデーライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Um, thank you so much for coming to Yukihana Lamy's birthday live today!
え、早速ですが、1曲目スタートダッシュ、2曲目ブルーバードを聞いていただきました！
Um, right away, for the first song Start Dash, and the second song Blue Bird, you listened to them!
みんな、どうだった？どうだった？
How was it everyone? How was it?
ラミィダンス頑張りました！みんなダンス見てくれた？みんな頑張って、ラミィ頑張ったよ！
Lamy worked hard on dancing! Did everyone watch the dance? Everyone did their best, Lamy did her best!
え、そしてですね、本日のハッシュタグはこちら！じゃじゃーん！さあ、と雪花ラミィバースデーライブとなっております！いぇいぇい！
Um, and also, today's hashtag is right here! Ta-da! It is #YukihanaLamyBirthdayLive! Yay yay!
今日はこのハッシュタグをたくさんみんなつぶやいてもらえたら嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
Today, I'd be happy if everyone tweeted this hashtag a lot! Thank you very much!
え、それでは、ここからはですね、ゲストと一緒にお歌っていきたいと思います！あの先輩や、あの同期まで、最後までフォローたっぷりとなっておりますので、みんな楽しみにしててね！
Um, well then, from here on, we're going to sing together with our guests! From those seniors to those generation mates, we've got full follow-through till the end, so everyone look forward to it!
え、そしてですね、最後には告知もありますので、ぜひぜひ最後まで楽しんでいってください！それでは…
Um, and also, finally, there are announcements, so please enjoy right till the end! Well then...
うんっ、んまっ！
Mm-mwah!
キミの声を聞かせせ サア 冒険してみない
Let me hear your voice, why don't we go on an adventure?
タノシイコトハジメヨウ アソビタイ ゼッタイ
Let's start having fun, I want to play, definitely!
とうといっ！たいっ！たいっ！
To-tou-i! Tai! Tai!
アイワナ
I wanna
JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイビー
JOY and JOY and JOY and POP baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピープー
JOY and JOY and JOY and HAPPY people
ヨワムシナンカジャナイ ジシンアリゲニピースサイン
I'm not a wimp, confidently give a peace sign
キミノヒトミニキスシテ ワライタイ ゼッタイ
I want to kiss your eyes and laugh, definitely!
とうといっ！たいっ！たいっ！
To-tou-i! Tai! Tai!
アイワナ
I wanna
JOY と JOY と JOY と YOUきなベイビー
JOY and JOY and JOY and YOU baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなSayイエー
JOY and JOY and JOY and HAPPY Say Yeah
君の心はそう もっと Do Do
Your heart is like that, more Do Do
僕の心もそう いっそ Good Good
So is my heart, even more Good Good
はじけてるんじゃない？ イッツ ジョイフル
Isn't it bursting? It's joyful
ぱぴぷぺぽばぶ〜
Papi-pu-pe-po-babu~
イエーイ！
Yeah!
JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイビー
JOY and JOY and JOY and POP baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピープー
JOY and JOY and JOY and HAPPY people
ドキドキしちゃうの なんだろウ
Why is my heart pounding?
ゾキゾキしちゃうの なんだろウ
Why is it throbbing?
この指に 止まるのは どんな運命なんだ ぜんぶ知りたいな
What kind of fate stops on this finger? I want to know it all
じょいふるだって終わっちゃう エビバディいつか終わっちゃう
Even joyful will end, everyone will end someday
いついつも このトキも 最終型は きっと修正なしで
Always, even now, the final version surely without correction
どぅ We Do We Do We Do Do
Do We Do We Do We Do Do
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺ 痛いっ！
Papi-pu-pe-po, papi-pu-pe, it hurts!
とぅいっ！たいっ！たいっ！
To-i! Tai! Tai!
アイワナ
I wanna
JOY と JOY と JOY と YOUきなベイビー
JOY and JOY and JOY and YOU baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなSayイエー
JOY and JOY and JOY and HAPPY Say Yeah
君の心はそう もっと Do Do
Your heart is like that, more Do Do
僕の心もそう いっそ Good Good
So is my heart, even more Good Good
はじけてるんじゃない？ イッツ ジョイフル
Isn't it bursting? It's joyful
ぱぴぷぺぽばぶ〜
Papi-pu-pe-po-babu~
JOY
JOY と JOY と JOY と POPなベイビー
JOY and JOY and JOY and POP baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなピープー
JOY and JOY and JOY and HAPPY people
ドキドキしちゃうの なんだろウ
Why is my heart pounding?
ゾキゾキしちゃうの なんだろウ
Why is it throbbing?
この指に 止まるのは どんな運命なんだ ぜんぶ知りたいな
What kind of fate stops on this finger? I want to know it all
じょいふるだって終わっちゃう エビバディいつか終わっちゃう
Even joyful will end, everyone will end someday
いついつも このトキも 最終型は きっと修正なしで
Always, even now, the final version surely without correction
どぅ We Do We Do We Do Do
Do We Do We Do We Do Do
ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺ 痛いっ！
Papi-pu-pe-po, papi-pu-pe, it hurts!
とぅいっ！たいっ！たいっ！
To-i! Tai! Tai!
アイワナ
I wanna
JOY と JOY と JOY と YOUきなベイビー
JOY and JOY and JOY and YOU baby
JOY と JOY と JOY と HAPPYなSayイエー
JOY and JOY and JOY and HAPPY Say Yeah
君の心はそう もっと Do Do
Your heart is like that, more Do Do
僕の心もそう いっそ Good Good
So is my heart, even more Good Good
はじけてるんじゃない？ イッツ ジョイフル
Isn't it bursting? It's joyful
ぱぴぷぺぽばぶ〜
Papi-pu-pe-po-babu~
キミの声を聞かせ,
Let me hear your voice, come on!
さあ 冒険しよ,
Why don't we have an adventure?
楽しもう!
Let's get the fun started!
ラミちゃん おめでとう!
Lamy-chan, congratulations!
お誕生日 おめでとう!
Happy birthday!
おめでとうだね 頑張って頑張って!
Congratulations! Do your best!
みんなみんな 頑張った!
Everyone, do your best!
やったー!
Woohoo!
ていうことで「アイカギ」
And with that, let's do "Aikagi"
オーケーぶるの!
Okey-dokey!
みんなで 盛り上がっていきましょー!
Everyone, let's go! Let's get hyped!
イェーイ!
Yay!
よし、かんかん!
Alright, Kansai—
待って待って待って待って!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
疲れてるの、待って!
You're tired, wait, wait!
待って待って待って待って!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
ちょっとあと数分!
Wait, give us a few minutes!
何やりたいの?
What do you want to do?
まず深呼吸させて!
First, let's take a deep breath.
ていうことで!
And with that—
そう、ネコのラミィ ちょっと実はお誕生日なので!
So, Lamy, today is actually your birthday, right?
えっ?
Wait, what?
さっきお見せして…!
I just saw you!
そうね、おめでとう!
That's right, congratulations!
ありがとうございます!
Thank you very much!
記念写真を撮りたいなと!
I want to take a commemorative photo!
どういうポーズで撮りたい?
What kind of pose should we do?
あ、でも…!
Oh, but—
後ろのね、みんなでいい感じに!
Let's all do a nice pose in the back!
これやってみようか。
Let's try doing this one.
このへんかな?
Around here?
どう? いい感じ?
How's this? Good?
どうだ? いいね!
いい感じ!
It's a good vibe!
いい感じ? いいね!
Good vibe? Nice!
よーし、帰る! 帰る待って待って!
Alright, let's go back—
ちょっと、あれやろうかな。
Wait, let's do this one!
これよ!
This one!
あれやな、いいよ!
Like this? Good?
そうそう、チュウチュウなんたら!
Like this? "Chuchu nantara"?
いいよ! いいよ!
Good? Good?
じゃあラミちゃんの掛け声で…!
Alright, let's start with Lamy-chan's shout!
我々は出発するでな!
We'll start on three, okay?
えっと、何で?「オーケーブルー」でいくら?
And we'll go with "Okey-dokey!"
オッケー!
Okey!
ほんと? いくよ!
Alright, here we go!
オーケーブルー!
Okey-dokey!
あ、いいじゃない! いいな!
Is this good? Is this good?
もっと! もっと! もっと回れ! もっと回れよ!
More! More! Spin more!
ママ、何これ?
Mama, what is this?
ラミちゃん いきません!
We can't do this, Lamy-chan!
え? 夢餅?
Huh? Yumemochi?
今日、皆さんに迎えてもらいました!
Today, we were able to welcome you all!
イェーイ! ありがとうございます!
Yay! Thank you so much!
そして、ラミィお誕生日おめでとう!
And Lamy's birthday, congratulations!
ありがとうございます!
Thank you!
それではみんなもっと盛り上がっていくぞ!
Let's get everyone even more hyped!
イェーイ!
Yay!
見つめ合って恋をして
Staring at each other, falling in love,
無我夢中で追いかけて
chasing in a frenzy.
だけどもっと知りたくて
Wanting to know more,
メレメレしてる
burning up.
願うほど謎が増え
The more you wish, the more mysteries increase,
思うほど熱になる
the more you think, the hotter it gets.
だからもっと飛び込むの
So I'll jump in more,
未開の世界は
into an unexplored world.
恋とか夢とか誰でも信じるけど
Anyone believes in love and dreams,
そこそこ攻めなきゃつまらないよ
but it's boring if you don't push yourself a bit.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
The borderline you can't quite reach,
難易度Gでも 全て壊してみせる
even at difficulty G, I'll break everything.
ギリギリmind さらなるGへと
The borderline mind towards further growth,
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能
consciousness melts, the body is uncontrollable.
いっちまうかもね
I might just go.
ふざけあった友達と
With friends joking around,
求めあったあの人と
and that person we sought each other,
また会える日のためにギラギラしてる
shining brightly for the sake of meeting again.
光るほど影ができ
The more it shines, the shadows form,
燃えるほど灰になる
the more it burns, the higher you get.
走るほど見えてくる危ないライン
The more you run, the dangerous rain becomes visible.
見つめ合って恋をして
Staring at each other, falling in love,
無我夢中で追いかけて
chasing in a frenzy,
だけどもっと知りたくて
but wanting to know more,
メラメラしてるよ
burning up with desire.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Limitless love, forbidden borderline,
難易度Gでも 全て壊してみせる
even with difficulty G, I'll break it all down.
ギリギリmind 更なるGへと
Limitless mind, towards even greater heights,
意識が溶ける 体は制御不能 行っちまうかもね
consciousness melts, the body is uncontrollable, I might just go over.
限界点なら 塗り替えていい
If it's the limit point, it's okay to rewrite it.
破壊と再生から 私が出来る
From destruction and rebirth, I can create myself.
ふざけ合った友達と
With friends joking around,
求め合ったあの人と
and that person we sought each other with,
また会える日のために
for the sake of meeting again one day,
ギラギラしてるよ
shining brightly.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Limitless love, forbidden borderline,
非日常だね まだ加速しているよ
It's extraordinary, I'm still accelerating.
ギリギリmind 限界点なら 塗り替えていい
Limitless mind, if it's the limit point, it's okay to rewrite it.
破壊と再生から 私が出来る
From destruction and rebirth, I can create myself.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Limitless love, forbidden borderline,
燃え尽きながら まだ輝いてみせる
while burning out, I'll still shine.
ギリギリmind あなたのために 未来のために 何度砕け散っても
Limitless mind, for you, for the future, no matter how many times I shatter,
愛することで 生まれ変わる
by loving, I am reborn.
愛されたくて 生き続ける
I live wanting to be loved.
ギリギリ愛 いけないボーダーライン
Limitless love, forbidden borderline,
生き続けてる
I keep living.
はい、ということで、見事先輩に来ていただきましたー！
Yes, so we were able to have Senpai come join us!
やったー！緊張したー！
Yay! I was so nervous!
えー、やったー！
Yay!
いや、だから こういうさ、やっぱ明るい先輩が来てくれるって...
I mean, having a bright Senpai like this come join...
めちゃめちゃテンション上がってさ！
Really gets my energy up!
いや、今回ね、トワ先輩をちょっとね、お呼びさせていただ、お誘いさせていただいたのには、実は理由がありまして。
Actually, there's a reason why I asked Towa-senpai to come join us today.
えーで、めちゃめちゃ丁寧な言葉遣い。
Such very polite phrasing!
いやね、あの 七夕のとき覚えてます？
You know, do you remember Tanabata?
七夕のとき、七夕の短冊に何、なんて自分で書かれたか覚えてます？
Do you remember what you wrote on your Tanabata bamboo slip?
待って、なんて書いたっけ？超忘れた。
Wait, what did I write? I totally forgot.
でもなんかを出した気がする。
But I feel like I put something out there.
え、なんて書いてた？え、いろんなホロメンと歌を歌いたいって書いてた。
What did you write? You wrote that you wanted to sing songs with various Hololive members.
おおー！
Ohh!
え、じゃあ違ったらどうしよう？あれ？なんて書いたっけ？
Wait, what if that's wrong? Huh? What did I write?
いやでも、それは、でも、それはでもしたいなっていうのはあったから...
Well, but, I did have the feeling that I wanted to do it, so...
あ、それは、あ、叶えてくれたってこと？
Ah, does that mean you made it come true?
いや、これはね、これをそのときに、実はね、歌歌いたい感じだったんだけど、なかなかお誘いするきっかけがなくって。
Well, actually, at that time I really wanted to sing, but I never had the chance to invite you.
なくって。そう！で、あ、誕生日、ライブ、トワ先輩と歌って...
I didn't. That's right! So, ah, birthday, live, singing with Towa-senpai...
皆さん、呼ばれちゃいました。トワ様でーす。
Everyone, I got called. It's Towa-sama!
え、実際に、それで、ごめんね、するーしちゃってごめんなさい。実際に、ラミィとちょっとね初めて歌う形になったんですけれども、いかがでしたか？
Actually, sorry for ignoring you, my bad. Since it's the first time singing with Lamy, how was it?
あんた、いろんな声、声持っててさー。
You have all kinds of different voice tones.
え、かっこいい！今日も！え、なんで急に、かっこいいのも歌えるし、かっこいいのを歌うって、めっっちゃもう武器やないかーい！
So cool! Today too! Wait, why suddenly? You can sing cool songs too, having cool songs as a weapon is amazing!
いや、テンション尖ってね。
Man, your tension is so sharp.
やっぱこうやってね、なんだかんだこう二人でコラボするっていうのもあまりなかったから。
After all, we haven't really collaborated just the two of us like this before.
確かに、なかんたかない。4人とかはあったけど。2人は初めて。
True, not really. We've had 4 people before. But just the two of us is a first.
やっぱ緊張すっから、今後やめるか二人。
Since we're so nervous, maybe we should stop doing pairs from now on.
なんでだよ！全く緊張してないじゃんよ！
Why'd you say that! You weren't nervous at all!
ほら、その中の良さをアピールするために写真撮りましょうよ。
Hey, let's take a picture to show off our good chemistry.
あ、いいよ。じゃあどっち行くじゃん？
Oh, sure. So which way?
え、ちょっと、2枚ぐらい撮ろうか。
Um, let's take about 2 pictures.
あ、2枚？どういうポーズがいい？
Oh, 2 pictures? What kind of pose?
え、なんか可愛い、あ、かっこいいのにしよっか。「いけないボーダーライン」の感じの。
Um, something cute—ah, let's do cool ones. Like the vibe of "Ikenai Borderline."
え、可愛いね、それ可愛い。自分でするのもなんだが...
Ah, cute, that's cute. Even though I'm saying it myself...
かわいいね
So cute.
かわいい
Cute.
も、お前もかわいいよ
You're cute too.
あっ、ありがたー
Ah, thank youー
後輩も褒めるから
Because I praise my juniors too.
このサムネイルのさ
As for this thumbnail,
あ、これ、これもやろうよ
Ah, let's do this one too.
おいおいおい、このきれいな、美しい
Hey hey hey, this pretty, beautiful...
あ、そうそうそうそうそう
Ah, right, right, right, right, right.
きゅるん
Kyurun~
ってことね、先輩ありがとうー！
So, senpai, thank youー!
イエーイ
Yay!
Happy Birthday
カラフル 作詞・作曲：渡辺翔
[Song: Colorful]
いつもモノクロだった瞳の奥の
Deep in eyes that were always monochrome,
景色捨てたら夢見つけた
I threw away the view and found my dream.
何もない世界で創る絆は
Bonds forged in an empty world
強い意志を与えた
gave me a strong will.
裏返した日常でまた走って行く先に
Running through flipped-around everyday days,
君はいた
ahead, you were there.
触れた心は輝いた 鮮やかな色になって
The heart I touched shone bright, turning vivid colors,
羽ばたくよ希望乗せて
taking flight with hope aboard.
無限に広がる空の下集まった 願いい守り進めば
Beneath the infinite sky, our gathered wishes protect and move forward,
まだ誰も知らない明日へと
toward a tomorrow no one yet knows.
引き寄せられるように覗いた瞬間
The moment I peeked as if drawn in,
光の糸は君包んだ
threads of light wrapped around you.
細く千切れそうな絡まった運命
Our thin, delicate, tangled strands of fate
きっとまだ変えられる
can still change.
間違えても信じた道は新しい景色を
Even if wrong, the path I believed in
照らすだろう
will light up a new sight.
巡る時の中笑って 様々な想い持って
Laughing in the cycling time, holding various thoughts,
始めようまた一から
let's start again from scratch.
辿り着いた僅かな奇跡壊れないように
To keep this fleeting miracle from breaking,
手を伸ばし繋げば ほら君は側でいつまでも…
if I reach out and grab your hand, you'll stay by my side forever...
まだ透明な私たちはどんな色にでも
We're still transparent and can be
染まることができるから夢叶えよう
dyed in any color, so let's make our dreams come true.
走って行く先に 君はいた
Ahead of where I started to run, you were there.
触れた心は輝いた 鮮やかな色になって
The heart I touched shone bright, turning vivid colors,
羽ばたくよ希望乗せて
taking flight with hope aboard.
無限に広がる空の下集まった 願いい守り行けば
Beneath the infinite sky, if I can go protect our gathered wishes,
君と誓ったあの日の記憶 今越えて過去から まだ誰も知らない明日へと
I'll overcome the memories of that day when I made a promise with you and go from the past now toward a tomorrow no one yet knows.
間違いでも 信じた道は 新しい景色を照らすだろう
Even if wrong, the path I believed in will light up a new sight.
巡る時の中 笑って 様々な想い持って 始めよう また一から
Laughing in the cycling time, holding various thoughts, let's start again from scratch.
巡る 時の中 笑って 様々な 想い持って 始めよう
Laughing through the turning time, holding various thoughts, let's start anew.
辿り着いた儚い奇跡 壊れないように 手を伸ばし繋げば
To keep this fleeting miracle from breaking, if I reach out and connect our hands,
ほら 君はそばで いつまでも まだ透明な私たちは
look, you'll be by my side forever. We're still transparent,
どんな色にでも 染まることができるから 夢叶えよう
and can be dyed in any color, so let's make our dreams come true.
走って行く先に 君はいた 触れた心は輝いた 鮮やかな色になって
Ahead of where I started to run, you were there. The heart I touched shone bright, turning vivid colors.
羽ばたくよ希望乗せて 無限に広がる空の下集まった 願いい守り進めば
Taking flight with hope aboard, beneath the infinite sky, our gathered wishes protect and move forward.
君と誓ったあの日の記憶 今越えて過去から まだ誰も知らない明日へと
Overcoming the memories of that day when I promised with you, going from the past toward an unknown tomorrow.
まだ誰も知らない明日へと
Toward a tomorrow no one yet knows.
はーい！
Hey!
いきなりそんな遠く行かない！
You don't have to go that far away all of a sudden!
そう、そうだよね。
That's right, yeah.
そう、実は...
Actually, yeah...
皆さんちょっとこの微妙な空気わかるでしょうか？
Does everyone know this awkward atmosphere?
微妙... 微妙な空気なんですよ、はい。
It's an awkward, awkward atmosphere, yes.
かなた先輩、おめでとうございます！
Kanata-senpai, congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
お邪魔します！ラミィちゃん、おめでとう！
Pardon us! Lamy-chan, congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ちょっとね、こう、みみ、みんな、どういう感じっていう感じかもしれないですけど
You might feel a little awkward...
ちょっとね、困惑してるんじゃないですか、この空気にね。
You're feeling bewildered by this atmosphere, right?
あの、これはですね、もう分かってると。僕たちもね、もうとっくにリハも何度もやって
Well, you know, we actually did ReHax multiple times before,
今よりもっとね、気まずいトークを何度も繰り返し
and we kept repeating this awkward talk even more than before...
いや、さすがにこれは、友達の友達か、ラミィ姉に会おうなとか言ってさ。
Well, I mean, you could say this is between friends of friends, like Lamy-nee, and...
今回ね、ちょっと距離感を感じたから、これ2回目のMCとなっております。
So since we felt that distance, this is our second MC session.
ちょっとあの、MCの理由が、MCに距離があるから。
Well, the reason for the MC is because there's distance between the MCs.
仲良し... 仲良し撮影会します。
We had a photoshoot where we got close!
今日はもう本当かなた先輩と、カラフルが歌いたくて。
So today, Kanata-senpai and I wanted to sing "Colorful".
本当にね、その、誘ってもらった時嬉しくって、この「カラフル」って曲は、僕は知らなかったのね。
I was so happy when you invited me, and since I didn't know the song "Colorful" before...
え、そうなんですか？
Eh, really?
そうなの。今回のために、覚えました。
I learned it just for this time!
いや、あの、かなた先輩ね、あの今回すごいたくさんハモリを...
And Kanata-senpai, you added so many ad-libs this time!
あ、そうなんだね。ちょっとオリジナルで入れてくださったんですよね。
Ah, right, you put them in originally.
気分今日が乗っててさ、この微妙に、微妙な空...
Your mood was really riding high on those ad-libs!
え、知らなかったんですか？
Wait, you didn't know it?
知らなかった曲で、そんで覚えてから今日が乗り始めて、ハモリ足していい？もっといじってもいいかな？って思って。
I didn't know the song, so after learning it, I started getting into the mood and adding more and more ad-libs!
そう、ハモリをね、あの、入れてくださったんですよね。入れさせていただきました。
So you added those ad-libs to your heart's content, and I let you do it.
ねえ、なんか、せっかく2回目のね、微妙な、じゃなくて、仲良し撮影会しましょう。
Anyway, since it's our second time, let's do an awkward close photo session!
あ、そうだね、そうだね。じゃあ、回を。
Yeah, that's right, let's do it.
近寄って、近寄って！仲良く... どうぞよし。
Let's get closer, closer!
あ、いいんじゃない？あ、いいんじゃないですか。後ろのイラストも愛で... かわいい、かわいい。あ、いい感じ、いい感じ。
Oh, this is nice, nice. Even the illustration in the back is cute.
5年後連絡取ってなさそうだな。
We probably won't contact each other for 5 years after this.
取ってるよ、取ってるよ！
Take it back!
取ってるよ！
We are taking it!
一生の友達になるかもしれないからさ。
We might become friends for life, you know?
ちょっとわかんない。
Who knows?
なんでだよ！そこはさ！
Why would you say that?!
そうなんだろうよ。
You think so?
そこまではちょっとまだ、あれだけど。
Well, we're not quite there yet.
これからね。
From now on, right?
そうだね、どんどん、どんどん仲良く。なっていく。
Let's get closer and closer!
なっていきますよね！何にもないです、何にも！
Right? Things will happen!
なんだこりゃ、なんだこりゃ！
What is this? What is this?
なんだこの、友達の友達感。
What is this "friends of friends" vibe?
じゃあ、ないじゃないですか！
Well, it's not like that!
ということで、じゃあ、次のゲストに行きまーす！
Then let's move on to the next guest!
はーい！
Yay!
はい！ありがとうございました！ばいばーい！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
ビジネスフレンド。
Business friends.
やめろ！
Stop it!
それでは、ここまでたくさんのゲストの方と歌ってきましたが、
So we've sung with many guests up to this point,
やっぱりね、最後は、ラミィの大好きなあの3人と、お歌を歌いたいなと思います。
but for the very last, I want to sing with those three people whom Lamy loves dearly.
それでは呼んでいきましょう。
Let's call them over!
ししろん！
Shishiron!
うぇーい！
Yay!
ポルカ！
Polka-chan!
あ、はーい！
Hi!
どうも、尾丸ポルカです！いえーい！
I'm Omaru Polka! Yay!
いえーい！楽しかったね、さっき。
Yay, we were just having fun earlier.
ねね、ねねちゃんだ！すごく面白かった、もう1回やって？
And Nene-chama! That was so funny just now. Can you do it again?
（笑）
(Laughs)
という、じゃあこれ、あ、ちょっと、っていうことね？
So, should we do that pose?
はい。
Yes!
私たち！ぽ・ら・も・ね！
"We are... Po-la-mo-ne!"
（笑）練習してない割にうまいね。
That was so good!
うまいね！今のね、タイミング良かったね。よく合ったね。
It really was! Your timing was great just now.
いいじゃん、じゃあもうこれで。
Well, that's good then.
今日、え？あれ？呼んでくれてありがとうございます。
Today... Wait, thanks for coming!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
待って待って、今言い忘れてたでしょ、そう！
Wait, you forgot to say happy birthday at first!
なんで！？
Why?!
決まったことに気を取られてちょっと忘れちゃった！タイミングはちょうどよかったねって。
You were too worried about getting the timing right!
いや、それがいいんじゃない、だったし。
Well, that makes it even better.
後ろね、誕生日にみんなが来てくれて、嬉しいよ、ありがとう！
Thank you everyone for coming to celebrate my birthday!
で、なんでここに私たちわ？
So, why are we here?
っていうかここは、どこだ？どこだ？
Wait, where are we?
そう、みんなね、ちょっと見慣れないかなって思うんだけど、
Well, you might think you're not used to this place, right?
うんうん。実はここは、おまるポルカサーカスの... 私のやつ？え！そうなの？
Actually, this place is Omaru Polka Circus... Wait, my own place?!
そうなの！イメージがちょっと違うかもしれないけど。
So the image is a bit different, huh?
いや、ここんなとこかな？
No, could it be this place?
あなたのところだから ここ
Because it's your place, right here.
すごい、で もえ、こんな感じで回収してくれたの？ラミィ
Amazing! But wait, did you set it up like this, Lamy?
回収した、回収っていうか回収したわけじゃないけど
I set it up—well, not set it up exactly,
なんかもう消すものを消してみたいな
but like, erasing things that should be erased, or something.
なるほどね
I see.
で、電気を、電気を、電気をね消して、
And then, turning off the lights—turning off the lights, turning off the lights...
あしたからポルカさんが寂しくなります、違う、え、いい雰囲気 にしました。
Tomorrow Polka-san is going to be lonely—no, wait, I made it a nice atmosphere.
ありがとうございます、綺麗にしてくださって。
Thank you very much for making it pretty.
え、ここは 何をするんだい？ ここで、うん、4人で
Wait, what are we doing here? Here, um, the four of us...
え？
Eh?
まあ、そうだな。はじめて、はい、うんうん。
Well, that's right. For the first time, yes, yeah, yeah.
歌を、う、歌いたいなと思って思いました。やったー！
We thought—we'd like to sing a song. Yay!
いや、初めてね、4人で、うん、歌を歌うね。記念だね、うん。
Yeah, for the first time, the four of us, singing a song. It's a commemoration, yeah.
何を歌うの？何を歌うの？
What are we going to sing? What are we going to sing?
えーっとね、みんなが好きな歌で、うんうん。ラミィたちがデビューしたのは何月ですか？
Um, a song that everyone likes, yeah, yeah. What month did Lamy and the others debut?
はい、はい、ぬんさん。 8月であります。
Yes, yes, Nun-san. It is August!
そうだよ。ポビーポビーポビーポビー、正解であります。ポビーポビーポビー。そう、 8月が関係している
That's right! Poby poby poby poby, correct! Poby poby poby. Yes, August is related.
あの歌を、みんなでね、歌っていきたいなと。
We want to sing that song together with everyone.
なんだろう。え、みんな知ってる曲かな？
I wonder what it is. Eh, is it a song everyone knows?
全員 知ってると思うよ。好きだ と思う。
I think everyone knows it. I think you'll like it.
secret base ～君がくれたもの～
secret base ～Kimi ga Kureta Mono～
[Title: secret base ～Kimi ga Kureta Mono～]
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
With you, the end of summer, dreams of the future,
大きな希望 忘れない
our big hope, I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出逢えるのを信じて
Ten years from now, in August, believing we'll meet again,
最高の思い出を…
the best memories...
出逢いは ふとした瞬間 帰り道の交差点で
Our meeting was sudden, at the intersection on the way back,
声をかけてくれたね 「一緒に帰ろう」
you called out to me, "Let's go home together."
僕は 照れくさそうに カバンで顔を隠しながら
I was shy, hiding my face with my bag,
本当は とっても とっても 嬉しかったよ
but I was really, really happy.
ああ 花火が 夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっとセツナク
Ah, the fireworks bloom beautifully in the night sky, a bit painfully,
ああ 風が 時間とともに 流れる
ah, the wind flows with time.
嬉しくって 楽しくって 冒険も いろいろしたね
Happy and fun, we had various adventures,
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
in our secret base.
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
With you, the end of summer, dreams of the future, our big hope, I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出逢えるのを信じて
Ten years from now, in August, believing we'll meet again.
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知ってたよ
Until the end, from the bottom of my heart, I knew you were shouting "Thank you."
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, smiling goodbye, it's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
夏休みも あと少しで 終わっちゃうから
Summer vacation will end soon,
ああ 太陽と月 仲良くして
ah, the sun and moon get along well.
悲しくって 寂しくって 喧嘩も いろいろしたね
Sad and lonely, we had various fights,
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
in our secret base.
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと知ってたよ
Until the end, from the bottom of my heart, I knew you were shouting "Thank you."
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, smiling goodbye, it's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
突然の 転校で どうしようもなく 手紙書くよ 電話もするよ 忘れないでね 私のことを いつまでも 二人の基地の中
Suddenly transferred, without knowing what to do, I'll write letters, I'll make calls, don't forget me, inside our secret base forever...
忘れないでね 僕のことを いつまでも二人の秘密の基地の中
Don't ever forget about me, forever inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して
Talking endlessly at the end of summer,
夕日を見てから 星を眺め
watching the sunset, then gazing at the stars,
君のほおを流れた 涙は ずっと忘れない
I will never forget the tears that flowed down your cheeks.
君が最後まで 大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'll surely never forget you waving goodbye with all your might until the very end.
だからこうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に
So, like this, in my dreams, for all eternity...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
With you, the end of summer, dreams of the future,
大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget our big hopes.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing we'll meet again ten years from now in August.
君が最後まで 心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew you were shouting 'Thank you' from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, smiling as we said goodbye, how bittersweet...
最高の思い出を...
With the most wonderful, amazing memories...
それはとっても…キラキラ、まぶしくて…
It was so... dazzling, shining brightly...
あぁ……
Ah...
私もあんなふうになれたらって……
I wish I could be like that too...
すごかった…
That was amazing...
えっと……生年月日、志望動機……送信！
Um... Date of birth, motivation for applying... Send!
お願いします！
Please!
あっ…
Ah...
歌は得意ですか？
Are you good at singing?
えっと……
Um...
お願いします！
Please!
あっ…
Ah...
やったー！合格しました！体力テスト合格しました！
Yay! I passed! I passed the physical fitness test!
えっ…
Eh...
みんなの前で歌う…
Singing in front of everyone...
私なんかは…
Someone like me...
えっ…
Eh...
待って、待ってください！待って…まだ私…
Wait, please wait! Wait... I'm not yet...
踏み出す…勇気……
The courage... to take a step forward...
でなかった……
I didn't have it...
どんなときも、強く、美しく……
No matter how painful, no matter what, strongly and beautifully...
私だって……
Even someone like me...
みんな…
Everyone...
お父様、お母様
Father... Mother...
私
I...
行ってきます
I'm heading out.
ドアを開けてください！
Please open the door!
お待たせしておりました、雪花ラミィさん、
We've been waiting for you, Lamy Yukihana,
さあ、あなたのステージへ！！
Now, to your stage!!
足が...
My legs...
それでは聴いてください。
Now then, please listen.
明日への境界線
Boundary Line to Tomorrow
夢の数だけ夢は 大きくなるんだって
Dreams grow as large as the number of dreams we have,
小さな頃から 信じてたはず
So I should have believed since I was little.
心がブレーキかけて 立ち止まってしまっても
Even if my heart puts on the brakes and stops me in my tracks,
ゴールは逃げたりしないから
The goal won't run away from me.
一歩ずつ ゆっくりでも 見失うことなく
Step by step, even if slowly, without losing sight of it,
前だけ見て 進めなくても 絶対にあきらめない
Looking only ahead, even if I can't advance, I'll never give up.
だって大切な仲間が いつもそばにいるから
Because my precious companions are always by my side.
行くよ！
Here we go!
明日への境界線を みんなで声を超えたい
Let's cross the boundary line to tomorrow together with our voices!
繋がる絆は離れない
The bonds connecting us will never break.
空回りして雨降らし つまづくこともあるけど
Though we sometimes spin our wheels, bring rain, and stumble,
手を繋いで 大丈夫 今日という日を信じて進め
Holding hands, it's gonna be alright—believe in today and press forward.
絆が深まるほど 夢は確信に変わる
The deeper our bonds grow, the more our dreams turn into certainty.
素敵な未来を描こうね
Let's paint a wonderful future.
一歩ずつ 焦らずに 強気なくして 空見上げて
Step by step, without rushing, with bold spirit, looking up at the sky.
この夜闇も いつかは晴れるからね
Because this darkness of night will eventually clear up.
道に迷って落ち込む私を 照らしてくれる
Illuminating me when I get lost and feel down on the road.
行くよ！
Here we go!
夢との境界線へ みんなで背の飛び込もう
Let's all leap across the boundary line of our dreams together!
想いを繋げて未来まで
Connecting our feelings all the way to the future.
遠回りだからこそ 痛く枯れることもあるけど
Though taking the detour sometimes makes us hurt or dry up,
ずっと一緒だよ 支え合った夢まで進め
We'll always be together—advance towards the dream we supported each other for.
さぁ描いた夢まで進め
Now, advance towards the dream we painted.
明日への境界線を みんなでせーの超えたい
Let's cross the boundary line to tomorrow together with our voices!
繋がる絆は離れない
The bonds connecting us will never break.
どんな未来が待っていても 必ず隣にいるよ
No matter what future awaits us, I'll always be right by your side.
どうか忘れないで
Please don't forget that.
さぁ明日を迎えに行こう
Now, let's go welcome tomorrow!
さあ明日を迎えに行こう
Now, let's go meet tomorrow.
雪花ラミィ誕生日記念2021 11月15日21時から販売開始します。
Yukihana Lamy's Birthday Commemoration 2021 goes on sale from 21:00 on November 15th!
今回の誕生日記念フルセットは記念ボイス1種、記念グッズが3種類。
This birthday commemoration full set includes 1 voice pack and 3 types of merch.
フルセット購入特典はなんとラミィ直筆サイン入り複製メッセージポストカードとなっております。
The full set purchase bonus is a message postcard with Lamy's autographed replica!
フルセットお迎えしてくれた方全員に直筆サインを入れるので慌てないでゆっくり注文してね。
I'll sign every single full set, so take your time and order at your leisure!
それでは商品紹介です。まず記念ボイスは、おはようからおやすみまでいろんな場面で使えるシステムボイスのセット。
Now, onto the merchandise introduction. First, the voice pack features system voices for every moment from morning to night.
そして記念グッズはねこみ先生描き下ろしのラバーマット。サイズは高さ34cm、幅60cm。
Next is the rubber mat illustrated by necomi-sensei, measuring 34cm tall by 60cm wide.
パソコンのマウスパッドやカードゲームのマットにも使えちゃうサイズです。
It's sized perfectly for a computer mousepad or card game mat!
そして高さ23cm、幅16.6cmの等身大だいふくぬいぐるみ。
And the life-sized Daifuku plushie, standing 23cm tall and 16.6cm wide.
もっちもちの素材を使っているのでたくさん抱きしめてね。
It's made with super squishy material, so give it lots of hugs!
最後は雪民ステンレスタンブラー。雪民さんがいーっぱいちりばめられた可愛いタンブラーになっています。
Finally, the Yukimin stainless tumbler, decorated with tons of cute Yukimins.
大福もいるのでぜひぜひ見つけてみてね。
Daifuku is on it too, so be sure to find him!
今回も細かい部分までこだわったグッズになっていますので、みんなお迎えしてくれると嬉しいです。
These goods have attention to detail down to the finest parts, so I'd be thrilled if you all welcomed them home!
最後に ちょっと恥ずかしいけど今日は雪民さんに手紙を書いてきました。
Lastly... it's a bit embarrassing, but I wrote a letter for the Yukimins today.
今日はラミィのために最後まで見守ってくれて本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for watching over Lamy until the very end today.
雪民さん、大好きだよ。
Yukimins, I love you all so much.
んーまっ。
Mwah!